Maxwell Muhanda

Software Engineer

ajaybullec@gmail.com

y

8

()

About

My name is Maxwell Muhanda, a full-stack web developer currently based in Kenya. My Passion for software is 100% driven by ideas i dream of and my want to make them a reality. I strive to deliver high quality code alongside a great user experience in every product I build.

I also do Digital marketing, particularly web SEO and social media marketing all inspired with current industry tools and the ability to create engagements over through technology.

Outside of programming, I enjoy travelling, video games and watching Football. I treasure the feeling of making wonderful memories.

Portolio

Instruct 7

An uber for legal services

Al Image Generator ♥ 7

This is an AI Image Generator built with Vue Js , Flask and OpenAI Image Generation Library



Personality Test O 7

Get to know your personality



Pong Africa 7

Telecommunication company Landing

Vue Calculator O 7

Vue js composition api calculator



Vue-Flask IPAddress tracker O

7

track any devices by IP Address



Work Experience

Instruct Backend Developer

Apr 2022 - Present | Remote

Backend & DevOps engineer

- Developed a Django REST api server to validate user registration and match lawyers to clients, being the main logic.
- Implemented AWS to allow easy iteration in company cloud infrastructure.
- Developed code following common security practices and development design patterns
- Ensured the performance, quality, and responsiveness of 6+ microservice containers

Pong Agencies Limited Digital Marketing & Software Development

Executive

Oct 2021 - Sep 2022 | Nairobi Kenya

- Launched SEO campaign for high volume and long-tail keywords that generated unique visitors and growth of company website and online store
- Led transition from AWS to Hostinger shared Hosting, saving company KSH 5000+ monthly and increasing load speeds by an average of 38%
- Monitored social media and Google SEO analytics to adjust post time, location, and various media to grow target platform by 20,000+ followers in less than a year
- Strategized, developed, and managed digital marketing across
 Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook

Office of the Attorney General Industrial Attachment

May 2021 - Aug 2021 | Nairobi, Kenya

Provided technical support on HR department

Skills

Frontend Typescript, Javascript, Vue, TailwindCSS

Backend Django, Flask, REST, MySQL, Nginx

Marketing SEO, Analytics, SEM, Social Media

DevOps Firebase, AWS, Linode, Docker, Kubernates

Languages Python, JavaScript, SQL

Education

Marketing, Bachelor of Commerce, St Paul's University

Aug 2018 - Nov 2021

KCSE, High School Diploma, Musingu Boys

Feb 2014 - Nov 2017

Certificates

Agile Scrum Master(ASM®), Simplilearn

2022-05-01

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing, Google Digital Garage

2020-10-01

Introduction to Git and Github, Coursera

2019-11-01

Interests

web3

Blockchain

Forex

Gaming

Languages

Kiswahili (Native speaker), English (Fluent)

Online Version

Last updated at December 30th 2022, 9:36:10 am